lhor O

Lublin, Poland

(willing to relocate to another city)

About me:

Data Analyst with more than 5 years of experience in extracting insights from terabytes of data, creating actionable reports and dashboards for decision-makers, conducting A/B tests, and using ML algorithms to solve business problems. Seeking a Senior Data Analyst position to create high-impact data solutions.



mymail@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/me

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Analyst / Data Scientist at Company 1

2021 - Present

Kyiv, Ukraine / Lublin, Poland

- Developed ML models optimizing ad campaigns with avg. monthly spend >\$10M. Being applied to more than half of total traffic, models increase CTR and visit rate by 80% and Viewability rate by 25%, while maintaining sufficient impressions volume and inventory diversity. (Python | LightGBM | BigQueryML)
- Built in-house A/B testing framework supporting 15+ metrics, producing comprehensive reports with stylish visuals. Time spent on experiment analysis and report creation was reduced by a factor of 3. (Python | Plotly | BigQuery)
- Created 20+ dashboards for decision-makers to assess key campaign metrics, inventory health, and pacing. Implemented an alerting system which helped to catch several critical bugs. (Looker I Grafana I Tableau I Airlflow)
- Compiled technical requirements for new data sources / ETL pipelines and was the point of contact for Data Engineers, built data pipelines as the sole contributor. (Airflow I GCP I AWS S3 I Snowflake)

Data Analyst at Company 2

2018 - 2021

Kyiv, Ukraine

- Developed over 30 dynamic dashboards, including ones with complex data schema/hierarchy and geospatial data. Dashboards were used by stakeholders all across the company, including C-level management. (Power BI I DAX)
- Implemented scripts to automatically generate Excel/PDF reports, streamlining reporting workflows for the entire Network Quality department and reducing reporting-related workload by 66%. (Python I Plotly)
- Enhanced analytical model used to select which Base Stations to upgrade based on network quality & financial parameters, yielding a 20% increase in average return on investment per Base Station.
- Utilized Deep Packet Inspection data to analyze mobile internet usage and presented actionable insights to management regarding the impact of events such as the 4G launch or COVID-19 on mobile traffic consumption.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in System Analysis

2018 - 2020

Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Cybernetics Faculty, Applied Statistics dept.

Bachelor's degree in System Analysis

2014 - 2018

Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Faculty of Computer Science and Cybernetics

SKILLS

- Programming Languages/Frameworks: Python (Pandas | NumPy | Plotly | Scikit-learn | LightGBM), SQL (BigQuery | Snowflake | Oracle), Airflow (Astronomer), Selenium, Docker
- Tools/Platforms: Power BI, Looker, Grafana, Tableau, Jira, Git, AWS (SageMaker I S3 | EKS), Google Cloud Platform (VertexAI | GCS | Cloud Console), MS Excel, GSuite
- Languages: English Advanced (IELTS band 7.5); German Pre Intermediate; Ukrainian Native